Guide to the Cannon Mills Records, 1836-1983 RL.00187
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Klumac Cotton Mills Series, 1922-1936, bulk 1934-1935
  - Boxed Files
    - Correspondence:
      - 1934, Jan.-Dec., 4 folders (Box 200)
    - Ely and Walker Dry Goods Co., 1934 (Box 200)
    - Financial Data and Related Correspondence, 1922-1934 (Box 200)
    - Financial Statements:
      - 1933-1934 Sales Account, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Franklin Textile Corporation, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Golding Brothers, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Holbrook, Roy L., Plant No. 1 (Sales Invoices and Correspondence for Klumac), 1935, Feb.-April (Box 200)
    - Laniado and Ancona, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Montgomery Ward and Co., 1934 (Box 200)
    - National Dollar Stores, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Penn Dry Goods, Co., 1934 (Box 200)
    - Receivership, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Requisitions, 1934 (Box 200)
    - Sales Invoices, 1934, Jan.-Feb. (Box 200)
    - Sales Invoices, 1935, Jan.-June (Box 201)
    - Sears Roebuck and Co., 1934 (Box 201)
    - Southern Textile Co., 1934 (Box 201)
    - Spiegel May Stern, 1934 (Box 201)
    - Walter Field and Co., 1934 (Box 201)
    - Weekly Production and Sales Reports, 1934 (Box 201)
- Norcott Mills Company Series, 1915-1928
  Minutes, stock certificate books, and stock ledger of this textile mill established at Concord, N.C., in 1915. C. W. Johnston managed the company for many years until the Cannons acquired control in the 1920s. The factory had 12,096 spindles and produced singled ply ball and chain yarns in 1927. It became Cannon Mills' Plant No. 10 in the consolidation of 1928.
  - Boxed File and Volumes
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1915-1922 (Box 201)
    - Minutes of Stockholders and Directors, 1922-1928 (Box 201)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-200, 1916-1922 (Box 201)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 201-259, 1922-1928 (Box 202)
    - Preferred Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-44, 1915-1926 (Box 202)
    - Stock Ledger, 1916-1928 (Box 202)
- P. M. Morris Real Estate Company Series, 1910-1953
  Minutes, correspondence, financial papers, cashbooks, and rent books by this firm at Concord, N.C., owned and managed in part by J. W. Cannon and other officers of Cannon Mills. Rentals and management of buildings for businesses, including the St. Cloud Hotel at Concord, are prominent in the records. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 202)
    - Correspondence and Financial Papers, 1915-1920, 2 folders (Box 202)
    - Correspondence and Financial Papers, 1945-1950 (Box 203)
    - Employee Income Tax Withholding Certificates, 1943-1952 (Box 203)
    - Financial Statements, 1910-1921, 6 folders (Box 203)
    - Index to Vouchers, 1914-1932 (Box 203)
    - Minutes, 1910-1921 (Box 204)
    - Monthly Settlements with John M. Cook, 1907-1931 (Rentals) and Cash Accounts for W. L. and W. W. Morris, 1923-1932, Morris Bros., 1917-1932, and White and Morris, 1927-1932 (Box 204)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Cashbook, 1938-1949 (Volume 195)
    - Rent Book, 1941-1952 (Volume 196)
    - Rent Statement Book, 1922-1928 (Volume 197)
    - Rent Statement Book, 1941-1953 (Volume 198)
    - St. Cloud Hotel: Cashbook, 1911, Aug.-Oct. (Volume 199)
- Patterson Manufacturing Company Series, 1893-1928
  Files include minutes, financial statements, inventories of goods and assets, stock records, sales, superintendent's reports, invoices, and records of the company store and an insurance agency. Account books include ledgers, financial statements and inventories, stockholder records, statements of costs and superintendent's reports, cashbooks, early time books, production statistics, cotton records, and sales. patterson was one of the earlier components of the Cannon textile empire. James W. Cannon and J. Frank Patterson established the factory at China Grove, Rowan Co., N.C., in 1893. The mill, operator of 11,056 spindles producing sheeting and yarns, became Cannon Mills Plant No. 8 in the consolidation of 1928. Records of the Patterson Store Company, a general store, contain the names and accounts of many millworkers. Extensive invoices and checkbook stubs provide a rare sample of the nuts and bolts operation of a textile mill during its early years as well as filling some bookkeeping gaps. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Audit Report, 1907 (Box 204)
    - By-Laws, 1918 (Box 204)
    - Cannon Mills, New York City, Selling Agent, 1918 (Box 204)
    - Charter, 1893 (Box 204)
    - Charter Amendment and Proxies, 1906 (Box 204)
    - Charter Amendment, 1915 (Box 204)
    - Charter Amendment and Proxies, 1922 (Box 204)
    - Checkbook Stubs (See Boxes 227-229) (Box 204)
    - Cloth in Warehouses, April 4, 1914 (Box 204)
    - Corliss Engine by C. and G. Cooper Co., 1896 (Box 204)
    - Correspondence: 1893, C-Z 1894, O-Z 1902, Jan.-Dec., 4 folders (Box 204)
    - Correspondence: (Box 205)
      - 1905 1906, Jan.-Aug., 8 folders (Box 205)
    - Correspondence: (Box 206)
      - 1906, Sept.-Dec., 4 folders (Box 206)
      - 1918-1926 and undated (Box 206)
    - Letterpress Book, May, 1899-Sept., 1900 (Box 206)
    - Cotton Purchase Invoices, 1906 (Box 206)
    - D. K. Ferguson Patent Display or Exhibiting Boxes, 1903-1904 (Box 206)
    - Draper Corporation, Hopedale, Mass.:
      - Model E Looms, 1905-1907 (Box 206)
      - Specification for Loom and Parts, 1925 (Box 206)
    - Financial Papers, 1899-1908 (Box 206)
    - Financial Statements and Inventories, 1900, May 1-1908, Oct. 31 and Inventories of Land and Equipment, 1893-1926, Vol. (Box 206)
    - Insurance Agency Files of P. A. Earnhardt: (Box 207)
      - 1918-1927, F-Z, 3 folders (Box 207)
      - Aetna Insurance Co., 1918-1927 (Box 207)
      - Insurance Applications and Information, 1919-1922 (Box 207)
    - Insurance Inspectors' Requirements and Recommendations, 1902-1904, Including Blueprint of Mill, 1902 (Oversize-box OV3)
    - Invoice Book: (Box 207)
      - 1899, May 26-1900, May 27 (Includes occasional letters) (Box 207)
    - Invoice Book: (Box 208)
      - 1900, Feb. 27-1901, May 8 (Box 208)
    - Invoice Book:
      - 1901, May 11-1902, Dec. 9 (Box 208)
    - Invoice Book: (Box 209)
      - 1910, April 4-1911, March 9 (Box 209)
      - Invoice Letterpress Book, May, 1904-Sept., 1906 (Box 209)
    - Invoices:
      - 1893, A-C 1894, A-C, 2 folders (Box 209)
    - Invoices: (Box 210)
      - 1894, D-Z, 3 folders (Box 210)
      - 1894, A-Z, Mounted, 3 folders (Box 210)
    - Invoices: (Box 211)
      - 1895-1896, A-Y, 5 folders (Box 211)
      - 1897, A-S, 3 folders (Box 211)
    - Invoices: (Box 212)
      - 1897, T-Y, 2 folders (Box 212)
      - 1898, A-C, E-H (Box 212)
      - 1899, A-H, 4 folders (Box 212)
    - Invoices: (Box 213)
      - 1899, I-Z, 4 folders (Box 213)
      - 1900, A-C, 3 folders (Box 213)
    - Invoices: (Box 214)
      - 1900, D-G (Box 214)
      - 1900, H-L (Box 214)
      - 1900, M-P (Box 214)
      - 1900, R-S (Box 214)
      - 1900, T-Y (Box 214)
      - 1901, A-W (Box 214)
      - 1902, A-B (Box 214)
      - 1902, C (Box 214)
      - 1902, D-H (Box 214)
      - 1902, K-M (Box 214)
      - 1902, N-P (Box 214)
      - 1902, R-S (Box 214)
      - 1902, T (Box 214)
    - Invoices: (Box 215)
      - 1902, V-Z (Box 215)
      - 1903, A-Z, 7 folders (Box 215)
      - 1904, A-C, 2 folders (Box 215)
    - Invoices: (Box 216)
      - 1904, C-Y, 5 folders (Box 216)
    - Invoices: (Box 217)
      - 1905, A-W, 7 folders (Box 217)
      - 1906, A-Y, 5 folders (Box 217)
    - Invoices: (Box 218)
      - 1907, A-B (Box 218)
      - 1907, C, 7 folders (Box 218)
    - Invoices: (Box 219)
      - 1907, D-W, 4 folders (Box 219)
      - 1908, C-W, 6 folders (Box 219)
    - Invoices: (Box 220)
      - 1909, A-Z, 10 folders (Box 220)
    - Invoices: (Box 221)
      - 1910, A-H, 6 folders (Box 221)
    - Invoices: (Box 222)
      - 1910, K-W, 5 folders (Box 222)
      - 1911 (Box 222)
      - 1914 (Box 222)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1893-1917, Including Stock Ledger, 1894-1897 (Box 223)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1918-1928 (Box 223)
    - Order Book, 1907-1908 (Box 223)
    - Sales Invoice Letterpress Book, 1902, Dec.-1904, Feb. (Box 223)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1-294, 1894-1905 (Box 224)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 295-598, 1905-1915 (Box 224)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 599-873, 1915-1921 (Box 225)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 874-1171, 1921-1925 (Box 226)
    - Stock Certificate Book, Nos. 1172-1218, 1925-1928 (Box 226)
    - Stock Certificate Receipts: (Box 227)
      - 1921 (Box 227)
      - 1922 (Box 227)
    - Stock Certificates Lost, 1906 and 1915 (Box 227)
    - Stock Ledger, 1915-1921 (Box 227)
    - Stock Transfers, 1906-1907 (Box 227)
    - Stockholder Lists, 1912, 1915, 1919-1920 (Box 227)
    - Superintendent's Reports, 1906, 1913-1914 (Box 227)
    - Checkbook Stubs for Dividend Payments:
      - 1894, Feb.-1896, Nov. (Box 227)
      - 1895, May-1898, Nov. (Box 227)
      - 1898, Nov.-1901, May (Box 227)
      - 1906, May-1908, May (Box 227)
      - 1912, May-1915, June (Box 227)
      - 1915, June-1918, July (Box 227)
    - Checkbook Stubs for Dividend Payments: (Box 228)
      - June, 1923-Jan., 1925 (Box 228)
    - Checkbook Stubs:
      - 1906, March-Sept. (Box 228)
      - 1906, Sept.-Dec. (Box 228)
      - 1908, Oct.-1909, Jan. (Box 228)
      - 1915, Jan.-March (Box 228)
      - 1915, March-June (Box 228)
      - 1915, June-Oct. (Box 228)
      - 1915, Oct.-Nov. (Box 228)
      - 1915, Nov.-Dec. (Box 228)
      - 1915, Dec.-1916, Feb. (Box 228)
      - 1916, Feb.-May (Box 228)
      - 1926, May-Oct. (Box 228)
      - 1916, Oct. (Box 228)
      - 1916, Oct.-Nov. (Box 228)
      - 1916, Nov.-Dec. (Box 228)
      - 1916, Dec.-1917, March (Box 228)
      - 1918, Feb.-June (Box 228)
      - 1918, June-Sept. (Box 228)
      - 1918, Sept.-Oct. (Box 228)
      - 1918, Oct.-Nov. (Box 228)
      - 1918, Nov.-1919, Feb. (Box 228)
      - 1920, March-Oct. (Box 228)
      - 1920, Oct.-1921, April (Box 228)
    - Checkbook Stubs for Cabarrus Savings Bank: (Box 229)
      - 1897, April-1898, Aug. (Box 229)
      - 1899, March-Aug. (Box 229)
      - 1900, Oct-1901, April (Box 229)
      - 1901, July-1903, Dec. (Box 229)
      - 1902, Nov.-1903, March (Box 229)
      - 1903, Sept.-1904, April (Box 229)
      - 1905, March-1906, Feb. (Box 229)
      - 1907, Nov.-1908, July (Box 229)
      - 1915, April-Nov. (Box 229)
      - 1915, Nov.-1916, Sept. (Box 229)
      - 1920, July-1921, June (Box 229)
      - 1922, May-1923, March (Box 229)
      - 1923, March-1924, Jan. (Box 229)
    - Paterson Store Company (Box 229)
    - Audit Report, 1907 (Box 230)
    - Country Ledger No. 3, 1898, March-Dec. (Box 230)
    - Ledger No. 4, 1898, March-Dec. (Box 230)
    - Ledger No. 6, 1901-1903 (A small number of pages from index and accounts only) (Box 231)
    - Country Ledger No. 7, 1903-1908 (bulk, 1903-1907) (Box 231)
    - Checkbook Stubs: 1901, April-Oct. 1906, Nov.-1907, April (Box 231)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Ledger No. 1, 1893-1899, Including Stockholder Ledger Accounts, 1893- 1915 (Volume 200)
    - Ledger No. 2, 1899-1905 (Volume 201)
    - Financial Statements and Inventories, 1909, April 30,- 1922, Dec. 31, and Inventories of Equipment Built or Acquired, 1880-1953 (Volume 202)
    - Statement Book (Costs and Superintendent's Reports), 1900, Jan.-1901, April (Volume 203)
    - Statement Book (Costs and Superintendent's Reports), 1902, Sept.-1903, Dec. (Volume 204)
    - Cashbook No. 1, 1893, May-1897, June (Volume 205)
    - Cashbook No. 3, 1899, July-1900, Oct. (Volume 206)
    - Cashbook, 1907, Feb.-1908, Nov. (Volume 207)
    - Cashbook, 1909, March-1920, Nov. (Volume 208)
    - Stockholder Ledger, 1915-1928 (Volume 209)
    - Stockholder Ledger (Closed Out Accounts), 1915-1928 (Volume 210)
    - Biweekly Reports for Kannapolis Plant, 1909, May-1915, July (Volume 211)
    - Time Book, 1894, Aug.-1899, Feb. (Includes Map of Mill Village and Names of Residents) (Volume 212)
    - Time Book, 1899, Feb. 25-Dec. 30, Biweekly Production Statistics, 1912, Jan.-1915, July and Personnel, Wage, and Hour Statistics, 1912-1920 (Volume 213)
    - Cotton Record Book, 1903-1909 (Volume 214)
    - Cotton Record Book, 1918-1928 (Volume 215)
    - Order Book No. 2 (Sales), 1902-1906 (Volume 216)
    - Shipping Invoices, 1947, July-Dec. (Volume 217)
- Rowan County Farm Life School Series, 1913-1922
  Correspondence, financial papers, and construction and equipment records, and also some material relating to students, trustees, and state requirements. Officers of Patterson Manufacturing Co. were associated with this school, an early public high school and boarding school designed to teach agriculture and domestic science as well as academic subjects to boys and girls. Includes information on other farm life schools in the state. Charlotte architect Charles C. Hook designed at least two buildings. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Information Folder (Box 232)
  - Checkbook Stubs, 1914, March-1915, Jan. and 1915, Oct.-1916, June (Box 232)
  - Contracts, Specifications, etc., 1914-1919 (Box 232)
  - Correspondence: 1913-1922, 4 folders (Box 232)
  - Farm Shop Equipment for North Carolina Schools of Vocational Agriculture (Minimum Requirements), undated (Box 232)
  - Financial Statements, 1914-1921 (Box 232)
  - Holbrooks and Bradshaw, Building Construction, Time Sheets and Invoices, 1914-1915 (Box 232)
  - Invoices, Receipts, etc.:
    - 1914, C-S (Box 232)
    - 1915, A-C (Box 232)
  - Invoices, Receipts, etc.:
    - 1915, D-W and Misc., 3 folders (Box 233)
    - 1916, B-S (Box 233)
    - 1919, A-Y, 3 folders (Box 233)
    - 1920, A-W (Box 233)
  - Invoices, Receipts, etc.: (Box 234)
    - 1921, A-W (Box 234)
    - 1922, A-Y (Box 234)
  - Labor Time Sheets and Receipts, 1913-1922 (Box 234)
  - Miscellaneous Legal and Financial Papers, 1914-1921 (Box 234)
  - S. E. Brown, General Contractor and Builder: Payroll Time Sheets for Workers, 1919-1920 (Box 234)
  - Student Lists, ca. 1919-1921, Enrollment Statistics, 1915, and List of Farm Life Schools in N.C., ca. 1914-1915 (Box 234)
  - Trustees Minutes, 1919, March 25 (Box 234)
- Social Circle Cotton Mills Co. Series, 1913-1971
  Chiefly minute books, ledgers, general journals, trial balances, bank ledgers, cash receipts journals, cash disbursements journals, sheeting shipments, credit memorandums, and accounts receivable cashbook of this textile mill established at Social Circle, Walton Co., Ga., in 1913. Cannon interests had acquired the mill by 1915, and they operated it until merger with Cannon Mills and liquidation in 1983. There were 15,264 spindles producing wide sheetings in 1957. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 234)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 234)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1930-1956 (Box 234)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1957-1978 (Box 234)
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1979-1983 (Box 235)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Current Ledger No. 1, 1913-1930 (bulk 1920s-1930) (Volume 218)
    - Control Book No. 3, 1926, Oct-1930, Dec. (Volume 219)
    - Income, Manufacturing, and General and Administrative Expenses Accounts Ledgers, 1931-1945, and Depreciation Schedule, 1926-1934 (Volume 220)
    - General Journal, 1935, Jan.-1942, May (Volume 221)
    - General Journal, 1942, June-1946, Aug. (Volume 222)
    - General Journal, 1946, Sept.-1954, Nov. (Volume 223)
    - General Journal, 1954, Dec.-1962, July (Volume 224)
    - General Journal, 1962, Aug.-1970, Sept. (Volume 225)
    - General Journal, 1970, Oct.-1971, March (Volume 226)
    - Trial Balance Book, Manufacturing Expense, Administrative and General Expense, Income, and Accounts Receivable Others Accounts, 1931, Jan.-1948, Nov. (Volume 227)
    - Trial Balance Book of Manufacturing Expense, Administrative and General Expense, Income, and Accounts Receivable Others Accounts, 1948, Dec.- 1960, Nov. (Volume 228)
    - Bank Ledger, 1931, Jan.-1932, March (Included in Imperial Cotton Mills Bank Ledger No. 5, 1926-1932) (Volume 167)
    - Bank Ledger No. 1, 1932, March-1944, April (Volume 229)
    - Bank Ledger No. 2, 1944, May-1957, March (Volume 230)
    - Bank Ledger No. 5, 1967, Jan.-1971, May (Volume 231)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1939, Dec.-1945, Nov. (Volume 232)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1945, Dec.-1957, Nov. (Volume 233)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1957, Dec.-1963, Nov. (Volume 234)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1963, Dec.-1970, Feb. (Volume 235)
    - Cash Receipts Journal, 1970, March-1971, April (Volume 236)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 1, 1931, Jan.-1934, April (Volume 237)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 2, 1934, May-1937, May (Volume 238)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 3, 1937, June-1940, Sept. (Volume 239)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 4, 1940, Oct.-1943, May (Volume 240)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 5, 1943, June-1946, May (Volume 241)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 6, 1946, June-1949, June (Volume 242)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 7, 1949, July-1952, Nov. (Volume 243)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 8, 1952, Dec.-1955, Nov. (Volume 244)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 9, 1955, Dec.-1959, Jan. (Volume 245)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 10, 1959, Feb.-1962, April (Volume 246)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 11, 1962, May-1966, Aug. (Volume 247)
    - Cash Disbursements Journal No. 12, 1966, Sept.- 1971, April (Volume 248)
    - Sheeting Shipments, 1928-1934 (Volume 249)
    - Credit Menorandums, 1932-1956 (Volume 250)
    - Accounts Receivable Cashbook, 1932, Sept.-1939, Nov. (Volume 251)
- Swink Manufacturing Company Series, 1897-1947
  Account books, clippings, cotton contracts, correspondence, financial papers, legal papers, and payroll and tax lists concern the management of the property, farm lands, and buildings in Rowan Co., N.C., of this textile mill incorporated in 1923 by William Joshua Swink and Charles A. Cannon but never built. Swink Manufacturing was dissolved in 1931, and the partnership of Cannon and Swink took over its assets. Checkbook stubs record laborers' wages as well as other financial matters. Files arranged alphabetically and volumes shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 235)
    - Cannon and Swink, Account Book, 1935-1947 (Box 235)
    - Cannon and Swink, Checkbook Stubs, 1934, June-1947, Jan. (Box 235)
    - Checkbook Stubs (Business and Personal):
      - 1899, Nov.-1934, May 1923, April-1929, July (Box 235)
      - 1936, Jan.-1939, Aug. (Box 235)
      - 1939, Jan.-June (Box 235)
      - 1939, July-Aug. (Box 235)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 236)
    - Cotton Option-Benefit or Benefit Contracts, 1925, 1933 (Box 236)
    - Correspondence:
      - 1901-1927 (Box 236)
      - 1928-1933, 1939 (Box 236)
    - Financial Statements:
      - 1923-1932 (Box 236)
    - Invoices, Bills, Receipts, etc.:
      - 1923-1925(?) and undated (All from same box) (Box 236)
      - 1925-1934 and undated, 7 folders (Box 236)
    - Legal Papers:
      - 1897-1939 and undated (Box 236)
    - Mill Village Planning, 1923 (Box 237)
    - Payroll, 1914-1927 and undated (Box 237)
    - Swink, William Joshua:
      - Financial Papers, 1938 and undated (Box 237)
    - Taxes, 1923-1932 (Box 237)
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Swink, William Joshua: Personal Ledger, 1910-1939 (bulk, 1929-1939) (Volume 252)
    - Swink Manufacturing Company, Ledger, 1923-1934 (Volume 253)
    - Swink Manufacturing Company, Cashbook and Journal, 1923-1935, Including Trial Balances, 1927-1934 (Volume 254)
- Trading and Commission Company Series, 1916-1942
  Chiefly financial and legal papers of this selling agency and holding company that the Cannons incorporated in 1916, operated mostly in 1916-1917, and continued until liquidation in 1942. Files arranged alphabetically and volume shelved numerically.
  - Boxed Files and Volumes
    - Information Folder (Box 237)
    - Bank Statements, 1933-1942, 3 folders (Box 237)
    - Cashbook, 1916-1934 (Box 237)
    - Certificate of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1916 (Box 237)
    - Checkbook, 1916-1942 (Box 237)
    - Correspondence and Financial Papers, 1916-1942 (Box 237)
    - Taxes, 1916-1941, 3 folders (Box 238)
  - Volume Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Stock Certificate Book, 1916 (Volume 225)
- Travora Textiles, Inc., Series, 1961-1967
  Minute book of stockholders and directors of this company that operated plants at Graham and Haw River, N.C. The Cannons were associated with this mill after its incorporation in 1949, owned it by the 1960s, and operated it until liquidation in 1967. In 1962 Plant No. 1 at Graham had 3,456 spindles, and Plant No. 2 at Haw River had 9,476 spindles. The company manufactured glove flannels and suitings.
  - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1961-1967 (Box 238)
- Windemere Knitting Mills Series, 1899-1903
  Chiefly the minute book of the stockholders and directors and the bylaws of this hosiery factory established at Albemarle, N.C., in 1899 by James W. Cannon and others. The company became part of Wiscassett Mills at Albemarle in 1903.
  - Boxed File and Volume
    - Minute Book of Stockholders and Directors, 1899-1903 (Box 238)
    - By-Laws, 1901, and Invoice, 1899 (Box 238)
- Wiscassett Mills Company Series, 1898-1955
  Charter, bylaws, and scattered information about finances, stock, and managers of this textile mill founded at Albemarle, N.C., in 1898 by J. W. Cannon and David F. Cannon. The factory had 92,208 spindles in 1957 that produced combed single and ply knitting and weaving years. It was still operating in 1988. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boxed Files
    - Albemarle Merchants Association Resolutions, ca. 1922 (Box 238)
    - Charter and By-Laws, 1898 (Box 238)
    - Financial Statements, 1909-1921 (Box 238)
    - Groves, J.A., Treasurer, 1923 (Box 238)
    - Stock Certificate Correpondence, 1955, Jan.-Dec. (Box 238)
    - Stockholders:
      - Correspondence and List, 1920 (Box 238)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1895-1927
  Seven account books that have not yet been identified with a particular company record bank accounts, sales, and employee wages and hours. Volumes shelved numerically.
  - Volumes Shelved in Numerical Sequence
    - Bank Ledger, 1911-1913 (Volume 256)
    - Cloth Room Order Register, 1909, July-1911, June (Volume 257)
    - Cloth Room Order Register, 1911, July-1913, April (Volume 258)
    - Cloth Room Order Register, 1913, April-1914, May (Volume 259)
    - Order Book, 1895, July-1927, Feb. (Box OV2)
    - Sales Order Book, 1907-1913 (Volume 260)
    - Time Book, 1925, Feb.-1926, Feb. (Volume 261)